# EFSTATHIOS GALANAKIS

+447565648484stathisgalan@gmail.com Github|LinkedIn

#### **SUMMARY**

I am excited to use my industry and academic experience to bring cutting edge Computer Vision research to life. My interests lie in the field of Computer Vision with an emphasis on challenges involving humans, such as human pose estimation, human body segmentation, action recognition and action localisation.

#### EXPERIENCE

### Department of Computing, Imperial College of London

April 2021 - Today

PhD Student in Computer Vision

Supervisor: Prof. Stefanos Zafeiriou

As a member of the iBUG lab, I am currently working in designing and implementing algorithms for extracting data regarding the 3D face shape of a person by exploiting pictures of him from different angles.

# ARISE Project, Business School, Imperial College of London

February 2021 - Today

Research Assistant

I am working in a EU funded programme aimed to predict how much crop yield the farms of a specific area will have in a desired time period. My work involves exploiting data gathered from satellites and weather stations, exploiting them by using the latest machine learning algorithms whereas creating synthetic data for areas with low-data availability.

### ArielAI, London

January 2020 - September 2020

Computer Vision Scientist

My main responsibilities included designing and implementing innovative automatic pipelines in order to create new in-the-wild datasets by applying state of the art techniques to data across the web and planning human annotation tasks for ArielAI's annotators.

### Pobuca Ltd, Athens

May 2018 - January 2019

R&D, ML Engineer

I worked as the only ML engineer to develop a network for automated product recognition in pictures taken from supermarket shelves. This required designing Computer Vision algorithms and tools for easy annotation and creating both training and detection procedures alongside with back-end support.

## **EESTEC LC Athens**

November 2014-November 2015

I was a member of the board of the EESTEC's branch in Athens, a computer engineering students' volunteering organisation. While there, I took part in several events as a volunteer, some of those I help organising.

### **EDUCATION**

### Diploma/M.Eng. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

November 2019

National Technical University of Athens, Greece

Thesis Topic: Human Action Recognition and Localisation in Videos (Supervisor: Petros Maragos) Description: Given a video in which, a person performs an action, this architecture is able to predict a sequence of boxes which include the actor, alongside with classifying the performed action

# FOREIGN LANGUAGES

Greek (Native), English (C2), German (B1)

# TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming Languages Applications Python (Pytorch, Keras, OpenCV), C, CUDA, C++, Java, Latex, Emacs, Matlab